in this video we're gonna go over how to
在本视频中，我们将介绍如何编写苏打分贝的for循环
write a for loop in soda dB
first we're going to create a function
首先，我们要创建一个函数，该函数将执行我们的for循环
that will execute our for loop we're
going to name this function do and for
将这个函数命名为do，对于输入，我们将传递
the input we're going to pass in the
number of iterations to run to the write
运行以关键字开头的for循环的迭代次数
a for loop you start with the keyword
for followed by a parentheses this loop
for后跟一个括号，此循环应运行n次，其中n是输入
should run n times where n is the input
that we passed into this function so
我们传入了此函数，因此在括号内声明了一个
inside the parentheses we declare a
local variable that starts with 0 and
以0开头的局部变量，而该局部变量I小于
while this local variable I is less than
n it's going to execute the code inside
n一旦代码被执行，它将在花括号内执行代码
the curly braces once that code is
finished executing the variable I will
在此示例中，完成执行变量I的值将增加1
be incremented by 1 for this example
we're gonna create a counter that
我们将创建一个计数器，每次for循环为
increments every time the for loop is
executed first we initialize a state
首先执行，我们初始化一个名为count的状态变量，并在for中
variable named count and inside the for
loop we increment the count by one
循环，当您执行以下操作时，我们将计数增加一个编译并部署合同
compile and deploy the contract when you
execute the function do before input of
在输入10之前执行功能do，它将在内部运行for循环
10 it will run the for loop inside the
function 10 times and each iteration
函数10次，每次迭代将使计数器加1，因此
will increment the counter by 1 so by
the time the function finishes execution
函数完成执行的时间将使计数器增加
it would have incremented the counter by
10 now when you call the loop function
现在，当您再次使用输入11调用循环函数时，计数为10
again with an input of 11 the countin
will start incrementing from 10 and you
将从10开始递增，最后以10加上
end up with 10 plus you having which is
21 and that is a basic demonstration of
21，这是如何现在牢固地编写for循环的基本演示
how to write a for loop in solidity now
one thing you want to be careful of when
编写for循环时要注意的一件事是
writing a for loop is that you want to
make sure that your for loop doesn't run
确保您的for循环不会用完气体，换句话说，
out of gas in other words the number of
iterations should have an upper bound
迭代应该有一个上限，并有一个上限
and by having the upper bound to the
number of iterations you know that the
您知道for循环可以消耗的Monegasque迭代次数
Monegasque that the for loop can consume
will not exceed a certain amount so for
不会超过一定金额，例如，如果您有一份合同
example if you have a contract that pays
dividends to its shareholders you would
您希望限制其股东的股利
want to put a limit to
number of shareholders like 100 if you
股东数量，例如100，如果您不这样做，则此功能将用尽
don't then this function will use up
more and more gas as the number of
随着股东数量的增加，天然气也越来越多
shareholders become larger and larger
since there's a limit on the amount of
因为可以进入块内的气体数量受到限制，所以这
gas that can go inside the block this
means that this function will stop
表示此功能将在股东人数达到10时停止工作
working when the number of shareholders
is large enough and your shareholders
足够大，您的股东不会为他们不能
will not be happy that they can no
longer receive the dividend so when
更长的时间收到股息，因此在混合之前写时有
writing before the mixture that there is
an upper bound in this case we created
在这种情况下，我们通过限制
an upper bound by limiting the number of
shareholders that can participate in
可以很好地参与这份合同的股东
this contract well that's all I got for
this video thanks for watching and I'll
这部影片感谢您的收看，下次见
see you next time